{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Which of the following configurations is commonly seen in the case of the amino acids that form human proteins?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "L",
        "b": "D",
        "c": "Can be either L or D",
        "d": "Can be either R or S"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Amino acids Valine exist as ______ at neutral pH",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Cations",
        "b": "Anions",
        "c": "Neutral",
        "d": "Zwitterions"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Zwitterions are ______ at neutral pH.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Uncharged",
        "b": "Positively charged",
        "c": "Negatively charged",
        "d": "Charged, but net charge is zero"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. The titration curve of glycine represents ______.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Two buffering regions",
        "b": "Two pKa values",
        "c": "Both a and b",
        "d": "One buffering region at neutral pH"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. Which of the following amino acids exist as negatively charged ions at neutral pH?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Histidine",
        "b": "Lysine",
        "c": "Glutamic acid",
        "d": "Proline"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Which of the following amino acids exist as positively charged ions at neutral pH?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Histidine",
        "b": "Lysine",
        "c": "Glutamic acid",
        "d": "Proline"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },

    {
      "question": "7. Which of the following properties of a protein is least likely to be affected by changes in pH?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Primary structure",
        "b": "Secondary structure",
        "c": "Tertiary structure",
        "d": "Net charge"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. The dissociation constant of H<sub>2</sub>O at 25° C is ______.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "10<sup>7</sup>",
        "b": "10<sup>-7</sup>",
        "c": "10<sup>14</sup>",
        "d": "10<sup>-14</sup>"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. The naming is commonly done in the following manner",
      "answers": {
        "a": "pK<sub>a1</sub> – COOH, pK<sub>a2</sub> – NH<sub>2</sub>, pK<sub>a3</sub> – R group",
        "b": "pK<sub>a1</sub> – NH<sub>2</sub>, pK<sub>a2</sub> – R group, pK<sub>a3</sub> – COOH",
        "c": "pK<sub>a1</sub> – NH<sub>2</sub>, pK<sub>a2</sub> – COOH, pK<sub>a3</sub> – R group",
        "d": "Both a and b"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. Which of the following leads to the neutral charge of an amino acid?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Deprotonation of COOH and protonation of NH<sub>2</sub>",
        "b": "Deprotonation of NH<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup> and protonation of COO<sup>-</sup>",
        "c": "Protonation of NH<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup> and deprotonation of COO<sup>-</sup>",
        "d": "Both a and b"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
